ILGWU. Scrapbooks, 5780/160
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Scrapbooks
1910-1958.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/160
22.33 cubic feet
20.3 linear feet
Scrapbooks
This collection contains scrapbooks assembled by officers and members of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. The scrapbooks primarily contain news clippings.
5511139
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
July 2011
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, July 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains scrapbooks assembled by officers and members of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. The scrapbooks primarily contain news clippings.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780/127. ILGWU. America's Next Great Designer Award. Scrapbooks
5780/128. ILGWU. Women's Wear Daily. Scrapbooks
5780/160mf. ILGWU. American Labor Party news article scrapbook
5780/170. ILGWU. People v. Benedict Macri. Legal Transcript and Scrapbook
General
"Permanent deposit"
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States
5511139
- Loose Newspaper Scrapbook pages., 1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  February 1922 - April 1924. Yiddish.
- Loose Newspaper Scrapbook pages., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  April 1924 - May 1924. Includes press releases
- Loose Newspaper Scrapbook pages., 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Photocopies.
- Memorandum in Behalf of the Union, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  April, 1925
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  July 1924 - April 1925
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  May 1925 - February 1926
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  February 1926 - August 1926
- Out Of Town Newspaper Scrapbook, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  October 1925 - October 1926
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1911-1915 (Box 1a, Folder 1)
  Oversized scrapbook 1911-1915
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  August 1926 - December 1926
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  December 1926 - March 1927
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  March 1927 - September 1927
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  September 1927 - May 1928
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  May 1928 - March 1929
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  April 1929 - July 1929
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  July 1929 - September 1929
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  September 1929 - January 1930
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  January 1930 - March 1930
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  March 1930 - September 1930
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  September 1930 - July 1931
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  August 1931 - June 1932
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  June 1932 - July 1933
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  August 1933 - December 1933
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  December 1933 - April 1934
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  April 1934 - July 1934
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  April 1934 - August 1934
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  July 1934 - October 1934
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  October 1934 - January 1935
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  January 1935 - March 1935
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  March 1935 - May 1935
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  May 1935 - July 1935
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  July 1935 - September 1935
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  September 1935 - December 1935
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  December 1935 - February 1936
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  February 1936 - March 1936
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  March 1936 - July 1936
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  July 1936 - September 1936
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  August 1936 - October 1937
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  September, 1936
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  September 1936 - October 1936
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  October, 1936
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  October 1936 - November 1936
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  November, 1936
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  November 1936 - December 1936
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1936-1937 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  December 1936 - January 1937
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  January 1937 - March 1937
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  March 1937 - May 1937
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  May 1937 - July 1937
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  June 1937 - August 1937
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1937-1938 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  October 1937 - January 1938
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  January 1938 - February 1938
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  June 1938 - October 1938
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1938-1939 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  October 1938 - February 1939
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  February 1939 - August 1939
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1939-1940 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  August 1939 - January 1940
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  January 1940 - April 1940
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  April 1940 - July 1940
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  July 1940 - September 1940
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  September 1940 - November 1940
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  December 1940 - January 1941
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  January 1941 - February 1941
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  August, 1941
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  January 1942 - March 1942
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  January 1942 - June 1942
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  May 1943 - August 1943
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  December 1943 - March 1944
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  May 1944 - March 1945
- American Labor Party Scrapbook, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  April 1938 - December 1938
- American Labor Party Scrapbook, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  December 1939 - September 1940
- American Labor Party Scrapbook, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  May 1944 - October 1944
- AF of L Scrapbook, 1938-1939 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  October 1938 - June 1939
- AF of L Scrapbook, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  May 1940 - July 1940
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1944-1949 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  January 1944 - March 1949
- C.I.O. Non-Editorial, 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  September 1937 - May 1938
- C.I.O. Conference, 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- C.I.O. Editorial, 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  December 1937 - December 1938
- C.I.O., 1938 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  May 1938 - October 1938
- C.I.O. Non-Editorial, 1939-1950 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  June 1939 - November 1940
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  November, 1940
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1940-1956 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  November 1940 - December 1956
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1954-1958 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  March 1954 - April 1958. Loose photocopies
- Newspaper Scrapbook, 1959-1960 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  September 1959 - August 1960. Loose photocopies
- Womens Garment Strike Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  January 1936 - March 1936
- Womens Garment Strike Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Coat and Cloak Scrapbook, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  July 1933 - September 1933
- Press Comments Scrapbook, 1924-1927 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  March 1924 - July 1927
- Memorandums, 1924-1925 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Briefs, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Reports, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Cloak Strike, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Report of an Investigation, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Governor's Advisory Commission. Wages and Wage Scales, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Review of Constructive Publicity Campaign, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  February 1927 - May 1927
- Review of Constructive Publicity Campaign, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  February 1927 - May 1927. Photocopy
- Womens Garment Strike, 1933-1934 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  Oversized scrapbook- 10/12/33-7/34
- Facts About the Garment Strike, 1924 (Box 16a, Folder 1)
- I.L.G.W.U. Drama Department Scrapbook, 1934-1937 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  December 1934 - December 1937. English and Yiddish
- I.L.G.W.U. Choral Department Scrapbook, 1934-1939 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  October 1934 - April 1939. English and Yiddish
- I.L.G.W.U. Instrumental Department scrapbook, 1935-1943 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  January 1935 - February 1943. English and Yiddish
- I.L.G.W.U. Drama Department "Steel" Scrapbook, 1934-1935 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- I.L.G.W.U. Drama Department "With These Hands" Scrapbook, 1950-1956 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  June 1950 - June 1956. English and Yiddish
- Drama Department "Steel" and "With These Hands", 1939-1940 (Box 17a, Folder 1)
  Oversized scrapbook-4/30/39-8/24/40
- Organized Crime Scrapbook, 1937-1958 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  March 1937 - January 1958
- Organized Crime Scrapbook, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  August, 1957
- Unity House. Report and Data, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- I.L.G.W.U. 1962 Convention Scrapbook (Box 18, Folder 4)
  Yiddish and English
- Frieheit Cartoon Scrapbook, 1934-1950 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  Yiddish. October 1934 - June 1950
- Oversized scrapbook-U.S.Trade with Russia 1/9/20-1/12/21, 1920-1921 (Box 18a, Folder 1)
  Oversized scrapbook. 1/9/20-1/12/21
- Oversized scrapbooks from I.L.G.W.U. Strike 1910-1911 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Daily News Report and Womens Wear Daily, 1931-1932 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  Oversized scrapbook-strike clips. 10/12/31-2/17/31, 10/12/31-2/17/32
- Oversize scrapbook. Union label news clippings, 1958-60., 1958-1960 (Box 20a, Folder 1)